(LOW HUM AND BUZZ)
-(BUZZING CONTINUES)
-(SOUND WAVE)
(BUZZING AND
SOUND WAVE CONTINUE)
-(BUZZING CONTINUES)
-(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CRACKLING EFFECT)
(EERIE MUSIC RISES
THEN ABRUPTLY STOPS)
(STATIC)
(LOW BUZZ)
(FAINT STATIC)
-(CAMERA CLICKS)
-(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(NAREN BREATHING HEAVILY
THROUGH MASK)
NAREN: Okay, okay, okay, okay...
好，好，好，好...
(DEEP SIGH)
Okay...
好...
(BAG RUSTLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HEAVY SIGH)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SHARP BREATH)
Yes... Yes...
是的... 是的...
Yes, yes, come on...
Come on, yes! Yes, yes!
是的，是的，快點...
快點，是的！是的，是的！
Okay. Okay. Okay.
好。好。好。
(PANTING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
(METAL CART BANGING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DEEP SIGH)
Here we go, here we go.
我們走，我們走。
Okay. Okay. Fuck.
好。好。媽的。
Work. Work. Work.
動啊。動啊。動啊。
(BEEP, CLICK)
Standard... Okay...
史坦達德... 好...
Standard, can you-
can you hear me?
史坦達德，你...
你聽得到我說話嗎？
This is Naren.
我是納倫。
And I've, um...
我，嗯...
I've been separated,
uh, from the others.
我跟其他人...
呃，走散了。
And I think I'm okay,
我想我沒事，
but I'm not sure where I, uh...
但我不確定我在，呃...
I've never been out
this far before, so I don't...
我以前從沒走過這麼遠，所以我不知道...
Um...
嗯...
(SHARP BREATH)
There was this, uh...
這裡有，呃...
I didn't get a good look
at it, but there was, um...
我沒看清楚，但有，嗯...
there's something else in here.
這裡還有其他東西。
I need you guys.
我需要你們。
Okay? I need you guys
to get me, please.
聽見了嗎？我需要你們
來接我，拜託。
Fuck, I need you guys
to come out and get me.
媽的，我需要你們
出來接我。
Can you... can you come,
please, standard?
你能... 你能來嗎，
拜託，史坦達德？
(SOBBING): Standard?
史坦達德？
-(CLICKING)
-(DISTANT SHRIEK)
Oh, fuck!
噢，媽的！
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
Fuck...
媽的...
(LABORED BREATHING)
(BIRD QUACKING, CRASHING)
(SHOUTING): Fuck! Fuck...
媽的！媽的...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(EXHALES LOUDLY)
(DEEP SIGH)
Oh, shit... What the fuck?
噢，該死... 搞什麼鬼？
-(BIRD QUACKING)
-(NAREN YELPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(EXHALES LOUDLY)
(DEEP SIGH)
(DISTANT THUD AND ROAR)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CONFUSED MUMBLE)
(LOW MUMBLE)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING SOFTLY)
What the fuck?
搞什麼鬼？
(DISTANT BIRD CALLS)
(DOOR OPENS)
-(DOOR CREAKS)
-(NAREN GASPS)
(SQUEAL)
-(NAREN WHIMPERS)
-(FLOOR CREAKS)
(DISTANT RASPING BREATH)
(NAREN INHALES SHARPLY)
(PANICKED BREATHING)
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
媽的！媽的！媽的！
(PANICKED BREATHING)
Fuck!
媽的！
(PANTING)
-(LOCKED DOOR CLICKS)
-Fuck, fuck, fuck! Fuck!
媽的，媽的，媽的！媽的！
(GASPING BREATH)
(NAREN SHOUTS)
(MUFFLED, DISTORTED
SCREAMS AND SHRIEKS)
(STATIC)
(DISTORTED SCREAMS)
(CRACKLING, STATIC)
(TV CLICKS SHUT)
(EERIE, DREAMY MUSIC PLAYING)
(SQUISHING)
(MUFFLED, DISTANT RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING, CRASH)
(HEAVY MACHINERY RUMBLE)
(BROODING MUSIC PLAYING)
(WORKERS INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER, CLANKING
AND GRUNTING CONTINUE)
MARY: We all have
our loops, our habits...
我們都有
自己的循環和習慣...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
Behaviors that keep us
walking in circles...
...那些讓我們
原地打轉的行為模式...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
Reaching for the same solutions
...反覆尋求相同的解決方法
over and over again,
一次又一次，
thinking each time they'll
take you somewhere new.
每次都以為它們會
帶你走向新的方向。
But they don't.
但其實並沒有。
And still,
儘管如此，
it's the neural pathway
of least resistance.
這仍是阻力最小的神經傳導路徑。
A path you made.
一條你走出來的路。
It's the one that kept you safe
它在你的童年時期
when you were a child.
保護了你的安全。
You learned to push people away
你學會了把別人推開
before they could hurt you.
在他們傷害你之前。
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
And now,
而現在，
as an adult,
身為一個成年人，
you're still stuck
right where you started.
你依然困在最初的起點。
Alone.
孤單一人。
(CLARK SIGHS)
I mean, I'm not lonely.
我的意思是，我並不孤單寂寞。
I have employees
and... customers.
我有員工
和... 顧客。
I didn't say lonely.
I said alone.
我沒說寂寞。
我說的是孤單一人。
Yeah, well, I mean...
是啊，嗯，我的意思是...
(CHUCKLES)
I hurt people.
我會傷害別人。
I don't want to.
It's just the way I'm wired.
我不想這樣。
但我天生就是這樣。
So maybe I deserve to be alone.
所以也許我活該孤單一人。
Do you think anyone
deserves to be alone?
你覺得有人
活該孤單一人嗎？
I don't know, but, you know,
我不知道，但，妳知道的，
maybe it's not such a bad thing.
也許這也不是什麼壞事。
MARY: Being alone feels...
孤單一人的感覺...
deeply ingrained.
已經根深蒂固了。
I understand.
我明白。
You've had dreams
and a lot of resistance,
你曾有過夢想
但也遇到了很多阻力，
not a lot of support
in realizing those dreams.
在實現這些夢想的過程中
沒有得到太多支持。
And when we've experienced...
當我們經歷了...
hurt again and again,
一次又一次的傷害，
we start to expect it.
我們就開始預期它會發生。
It's like,
"Oh, I know this path.
就像是，
「噢，我認識這條路。
I know where it goes."
我知道它通向哪裡。」
So...
所以...
are you interested
in forging a new path
你有興趣
開闢一條新路
and see where that leads?
看看它會通向哪裡嗎？
Sure. Why not?
You know, I'm here.
當然。有何不可？
妳看，我都來了。
Great.
很好。
So I want to revisit
所以我想重新複習
an exercise we've done before.
我們以前做過的一個練習。
The role play.
角色扮演。
-Oh, the acting thing?
-Yeah.
- 噢，演戲那個？
- 對。
-I feel stupid doing that.
-I know.
- 這樣做讓我覺得自己很蠢。
- 我知道。
But we have a few minutes.
Let's, um...
但我們還有幾分鐘。
我們，嗯...
Yeah, let's try. A little bit.
好，試試看。就試一下。
(SIGHING): All right.
好吧。
MARY: Let's set the scene.
我們來設定一下場景。
Let's go back to the night
that Barbara left you.
回到芭芭拉
離開你的那晚。
You mean the night
she kicked me out
妳是說她把我趕出
of my own house?
我自己房子的那晚？
Yeah.
對。
I'm playing myself.
我扮演我自己。
-And I'll be Barbara.
-It is my house, by the way.
- 那我演芭芭拉。
- 順帶一提，那是我的房子。
I'm the one paying for it.
房貸是我在繳的。
-I know.
-(SIGHING): All right.
- 我知道。
- 好吧。
Okay, so, um...
好吧，所以，嗯...
(CLEARS THROAT)
I got home late.
I don't know how late.
我很晚才回家。
我不知道多晚。
Uh... She was already asleep.
Maybe midnight.
呃... 她已經睡了。
也許是半夜。
She usually goes to bed
before... It doesn't matter.
她通常在... 之前就上床睡覺了。
這不重要。
The point is, I was
in the kitchen, and, um...
重點是，我
在廚房裡，而且，嗯...
the glass, I broke the glass,
玻璃杯，我打破了玻璃杯，
and she comes running down
to see what happened, and...
然後她跑下來
看發生了什麼事，接著...
things escalated.
事情就越演越烈。
And how do you feel?
那你感覺如何？
Well, I was...
嗯，我那時...
I was drunk, and, um...
我喝醉了，而且，嗯...
I-I felt stupid, you know.
我-我覺得自己很蠢，妳懂嗎。
I was angry, because...
because I broke the glass.
我很生氣，因為...
因為我打破了玻璃杯。
Can you say that to me?
你能對我這麼說嗎？
-Uh, what, to-to Barbara?
-Yeah.
- 呃，什麼，對-對芭芭拉說？
- 對。
Um... I'm sorry that I woke you.
嗯... 很抱歉
吵醒妳了。
Maybe if you'd
come home earlier,
也許如果你
早點回家，
we could have spent
the evening together.
我們就能一起
度過這個夜晚。
No, I was...
I was working, you know?
不，我當時...
我在工作，妳懂嗎？
I came straight home after work.
我下班後就直接回家了。
MARY: Be honest with me, please.
拜託對我說實話。
I can smell it on your breath.
我能聞到你呼吸裡的酒味。
I had a few beers.
我喝了幾杯啤酒。
Define a few.
幾杯是多少。
CLARK: Well, it was a hard day.
唉，今天是漫長難熬的一天。
I needed to wind down.
我需要放鬆一下。
All you ever do is wind down.
你整天就只知道放鬆。
You're always at the store.
你總是在店裡。
You want kids, right?
妳想要孩子，對吧？
-We both do.
-Well, you know...
- 我們都想要。
- 既然如此，妳要知道...
having a family takes money,
養家需要錢，
which means someone has to work.
這意味著得有人去工作。
Unless being
a professional student
除非當個
職業學生
is considered a job these days.
在現在也被算作是一份工作。
That's not fair. You know
I had to take time off.
這不公平。你知道
我必須休學一段時間。
CLARK: Well, it's not my fault
if you can't keep up.
妳跟不上進度又不是我的錯。
How are you going to be a lawyer
妳要怎麼成為一名律師
if you can't even handle
law school?
如果妳連法學院
都應付不來？
Who do you think pays
for everything
妳以為是誰在支付
所有的開銷
while you're gallivanting
around campus
當妳
在校園裡四處閒逛
like a 30-year-old freshman?
像個30歲的新生一樣的時候？
I'll give you a hint: it's me.
我給妳個提示：是我。
I pay for your school, I pay
for your time off school,
我付妳的學費，我付妳
休學期間的生活費，
I pay for the roof
over your head.
我付我們住的
房子的錢。
-Can I talk now?
-No! No.
- 我現在可以說話了嗎？
- 不！不行。
Because I'd like to know,
what do you think happens
因為我想知道，妳覺得會發生什麼事
if you do manage to graduate?
如果妳真的順利畢業了？
You know, you pop out a kid,
then leave me with the bill.
妳會生個孩子，然後把帳單都丟給我。
(SNICKERING): Or am I stuck
at home changing diapers because
還是我得被困在家裡換尿布，因為
you're too busy working for
the first time in your life?
妳正忙著妳人生中的第一份工作？
-Now you're being cruel.
-I'm being honest.
- 你現在太殘忍了。
- 我說的是實話。
I thought that's
what you always wanted.
我以為那一直
是你想要的。
Just because you didn't get to
be an architect doesn't mean...
只因為你沒能
成為一名建築師，並不意味著——
I am a fucking architect!
我就是個他媽的建築師！
God damn it, I'm just stuck
selling shit furniture because
該死的，我只是被困在這裡
賣爛傢俱，因為
someone won't get off their
fat fucking ass and help me!
有人就是不肯抬起她那
他媽的胖屁股來幫我！
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
How do you feel, Clark?
你感覺如何，克拉克？
Who am I talking to?
我在跟誰說話？
-MARY: Me, here, now.
-You? Okay.
- 我，此時，此地。
- 妳？好。
(SWALLOWS)
Um...
嗯...
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to, uh...
很抱歉，
我不是故意要，呃...
(PUFF OF AIR)
you know, get angry
...妳知道的，發脾氣
or lose my temper or whatever.
或是失控什麼的。
MARY: I know.
我知道。
That's the purpose
of the whole exercise.
這就是整個練習的目的。
(CLARK HUFFS)
This is a good start.
這是一個好的開始。
To feel what you feel,
去感受你的情緒，
and then learn to identify
a new path.
然後學會找出
新的路徑。
Your reaction was
actually quite normal.
你的反應其實
很正常。
(BREATHES IN AND OUT)
Well, that's me!
嗯，這就是我！
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
-Well, ahoy there, mateys!
-(LIVELY FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)
嘿，各位水手們！
Tired of spending
your hard-earned doubloons
厭倦了把你
辛苦賺來的金幣
on overpriced furniture?
花在昂貴的傢俱上嗎？
Looking for deals
that'll shiver your timbers?
想尋找讓你興奮到顫抖的超值優惠嗎？
Then come on down
那就快來
to Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire,
克拉克船長的奧斯曼帝國，
the Santa Clara Valley's
聖克拉拉谷
favorite warehouse
and showrooms.
最受歡迎的
傢俱倉庫與展示中心。
You'll find bedrooms,
living rooms,
你能找到臥室、
客廳、
dinettes, dens
and bathrooms aplenty.
餐廳、書房
和浴室的豐富傢俱。
First-time homeowners?
We've got ya.
首次購屋族？
交給我們。
New parents looking
for Billy's first crib?
新手父母想找
比利的第一張嬰兒床？
We've got ya!
交給我們！
From the latest in modern design
從最新的現代設計
to the classic styles
of yesteryear,
到昔日的經典風格，
it's all here
and it's all a steal.
這裡應有盡有
而且便宜到像白送。
What's that, Polly?
妳說什麼，波莉？
You're worried about credit?
妳擔心信用紀錄？
Ha! Cap'n Clark says
no credit, no problem!
哈！克拉克船長說
免信用審核，沒問題！
Sail the high seas
of high quality,
航行在高品質的汪洋中，
and leave your money problems
at the door.
把你的金錢問題
留在門外。
Walk in today
今天就走進來
and get your dream
sectional lounger,
買下你夢想中的
組合沙發、
kitchen table, floor lamp,
and bed frame here
餐桌、立燈、
和床架
at Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire,
就在克拉克船長的奧斯曼帝國，
located at Capitol and McKee,
just off the 680.
位於國會大道和麥基路口，
680號公路旁。
Arr! Walk in today...
阿！今天就走進來...
(PANTING)
Kick your feet back,
...把腳靠著休息，
and enjoy an empire of your own!
享受屬於你自己的帝國！
For every sultan
deserves a throne,
因為每個蘇丹
都配得上一張寶座，
and we've got one
with your name on it,
我們這就有一張
寫著你名字的寶座，
here at Cap'n Clark's...
就在克拉克船長的——
-(CHAIR CRACKS)
-(CLARK YELPS)
BOBBY: No way!
不可能！
-KAT: Clark, you good?
-Turn the camera off.
- 克拉克，你還好嗎？
- 把攝影機關掉。
BOBBY: No, no, it's good.
It's outtake stuff, dude.
不，不，這很好。
這是幕後花絮，老兄。
-Turn the fucking camera off.
-BOBBY: Okay... Jesus...
- 把他媽的攝影機關掉。
- 好吧... 老天...
-(FOLK MUSIC CONTINUES)
-(CAMERA BEEPS)
You, uh, you need help?
你，呃，你需要幫忙嗎？
No, I got it, I got it. (GRUNTS)
不用，我自己來，我自己來。
Um...
嗯...
-Are we going again, or...?
-No.
- 我們要重拍一次，還是...？
- 不了。
Kat, you can open the store now.
凱特，妳可以開店了。
-(CLARK GRUNTS)
-We've been open.
我們早就開店了。
You know, dude,
I still don't get it.
你知道嗎，老兄，
我還是不懂。
Are you, like,
a pirate or a sultan?
你到底是海盜還是蘇丹？
-Just be good to establish it.
-I'm a... Shut up.
- 最好先確立一下設定。
- 我是... 閉嘴。
(GRUNTING): Piece of cheap
particleboard bullshit.
廉價的塑合板垃圾。
Clear this stuff up, will you?
把這些東西清理一下，好嗎？
Here.
給。
(NEW WAVE MUSIC PLAYING
ON THE STORE'S SPEAKERS)
(METER MAN SIGHS)
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
How's it looking?
情況怎麼樣？
METER MAN: Meter reads fine.
電表讀數正常。
If your bill's coming in high,
that's on you.
如果你的電費很高，那是你的問題。
What about the outages?
That happens after hours.
那停電怎麼說？
那都是在下班後發生的。
Don't know. Fluorescents
must be tripping a breaker.
不知道。可能是螢光燈
導致斷路器跳閘。
(GRUNTS)
I turn the overheads off
when the store closes,
我在關店時都會
把頂燈關掉，
before the power gets weird.
在電源變得奇怪之前。
Anyway, wouldn't that
just make the bills go down?
總之，那樣不是
應該讓電費降下來嗎？
(METER MAN SLOWLY INHALES)
Where's your breaker box?
你的配電箱在哪？
CLARK: I'm no expert,
我不是專家，
but I checked earlier,
and everything looks okay.
但我之前檢查過，
看起來一切正常。
-You said the lights flicker.
-Yeah, the whole store does.
- 你說燈會閃爍。
- 對，整間店都會。
-Huh.
-Just not at the same time.
- 哼。
- 只是不是同時閃。
One night,
I lose the power upstairs.
有天晚上，
樓上停電。
Next night, it's down here.
There's no rhyme or...
隔天晚上，換樓下停電。
完全沒有規律...
(METER MAN SIGHS)
(CLARK SIGHS)
Who the hell installed
this thing?
這東西到底是誰裝的？
Well, the building came wired.
這棟建築本來就配好線了。
I mean, it's dated,
but it's not that old.
我的意思是，它有點年代，
但沒那麼舊。
(BREAKERS CLICKING)
METER MAN: Take a look at this.
你看看這個。
CLARK: That wasn't there before.
那個以前不在那裡的。
Or... maybe I didn't notice.
Like I say, I'm no expert.
或許... 是我沒注意到。
就像我說的，我不是專家。
Why-why is it...
why is it going that way?
為什麼-為什麼...
為什麼它往那個方向接？
(METER MAN INHALES SHARPLY)
Better question:
更好的問題是：
what is it even connected to?
它到底是連到哪裡去的？
Huh?
咦？
CLARK (SHOUTING):
Kat! How's the power?
凱特！電源怎麼樣了？
KAT: What?
什麼？
Anything happen up there?
樓上有發生什麼事嗎？
METER MAN: Damn...
該死...
The rat's back.
老鼠又回來了。
-But the power's on.
-Yeah.
- 但還有電。
- 對。
I thought we killed the rat.
我以為我們已經把老鼠殺了。
We killed a rat.
我們只殺了*一隻*老鼠。
-So is this the problem?
-Don't see how.
- 所以這就是問題所在？
- 看不出有什麼關聯。
Power can't even go through
this part of the circuit.
電根本通不過這部分電路。
It's just...
它只是...
there.
留在那而已。
Like some schmo
just stuck it in there.
就像某個笨蛋
隨便把它塞進去的。
(METER MAN FLICKING BREAKERS):
Yeah.
是啊。
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
(LIGHT FLICKERING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
MAN 1 (ON TV): Do you ever feel
你是否曾覺得
like you're living behind glass?
自己彷彿活在玻璃背後？
Watching life happen,
看著生活發生，
but never really
stepping into it?
卻從未真正參與其中？
Maybe it's time
to open the window within.
也許是時候打開內在之窗了。
WOMAN (ON TV): You can be
the author of your own design
你可以成為自己人生的設計師
because we all deserve
another chance
因為我們都值得再有一次機會
to fulfill our dreams.
去實現我們的夢想。
The moment you believe
change is possible,
當你相信改變是可能的那一刻，
you've already begun.
你就已經開始了。
MAN 1 (ON TV):
Order The Window Within
訂購《內在之窗》
and the companion
three-part audio program,
以及配套的三部曲語音課程，
Guided Openings,
by Dr. Mary Klein.
由瑪麗·克萊恩博士帶來的《引導開啟》。
Available now
for $24.95 plus shipping.
現在只需24.95美元外加運費。
Call 1-800-555-0199.
請撥打 1-800-555-0199。
WOMAN (ON TV): It's never
too late to forge a new path.
開闢新路，永遠不嫌晚。
MAN 2 (ON TV): So, you're
still trusting paper folders,
所以，你還在信任紙本文件夾、
mislabeled tapes,
and a locked filing cabinet
標錯的磁帶，和一個上鎖的檔案櫃
that anyone
with a spare key can open?
任何有備用鑰匙的人都能打開？
Your business runs
on information,
你的企業仰賴資訊運作，
yet most companies treat
their data like clutter...
但多數公司卻把他們的數據當成雜物...
(DREAMY, DARK MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN 2 ON TV
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
ALIEN 1: That small blip
is not an asteroid.
那個小光點不是小行星。
It's a spaceship,
and it's on our tail.
那是一艘太空船，而且它尾隨我們。
-It's getting closer.
-ALIEN 2: Impossible, Rigna.
- 它越來越近了。
- 不可能，里格納。
They couldn't have spotted us.
We have our radar shield on.
他們不可能發現我們。
我們啟動了雷達護盾。
ALIEN 1: I know that, sir,
but they are gaining on us.
我知道，長官，但他們正在逼近我們。
ALIEN 2: Is it possible
Earth has a secret device
有沒有可能地球有一種秘密裝置
that can penetrate
our radar shield?
能穿透我們的雷達護盾？
-(TV CLICKS OFF)
-(ALCOHOL SLOSHING AROUND)
(SIGHS)
(TV CLICKS)
(SOFT GRUNT)
Piece of shit.
垃圾。
(SIGHS)
(REMOTE LIGHTLY THUDS)
(LIGHTS FLICKER ON)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
(LIGHTS FLICKERING)
(HUFFS)
(SIGHS)
(LIGHTS CLICK SHUT)
(INHALES, EXHALES)
(DARK MUSIC PLAYING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
MARY (ON TAPE): Why did you
do this to yourself?
為什麼你要這樣對待自己？
How did you get here?
你是怎麼走到這一步的？
Your consciousness
is a room full of memories
你的意識是一個充滿記憶的房間
that is constantly evolving.
不斷地在演變。
But as you walk through life,
但當你走過人生，
the untrained mind
can start to build walls,
未經訓練的心智可能會開始築起高牆，
put up barriers
設置障礙
to protect itself
from the outside world.
來保護自己免受外在世界的傷害。
(ENGINE IDLES)
It's a natural response.
這是一種自然反應。
Something we are
often unaware of.
我們通常不會意識到。
(CLARK SIGHS)
But if gone unchecked,
但如果不加控制，
it can leave you
feeling trapped.
它會讓你感到被困住。
You can become convinced
that the world outside
你會開始深信外面的世界
is better off without you.
沒有你會更好。
That you never deserve
the relationships you've had.
你不配擁有你曾擁有過的那些關係。
(CLARK SIGHS)
Resigned to watch
your life unfold
無可奈何地看著你的人生展開
from behind a lone window.
從一扇孤獨的窗戶背後。
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I can help you open it now
我現在可以幫你打開它
because the window isn't locked.
因為窗戶根本沒鎖。
The latch was never broken.
門閂也從未損壞。
Are you ready to step through?
你準備好跨出去了嗎？
So that you can reclaim that
which was once yours...
這樣你就能奪回曾經屬於你的一切...
and take back control
of your life.
重新掌控你的人生。
The life you want to be living.
那個你想過的人生。
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Unburdened by the traumas of the past.
不再受過去創傷的束縛。
Free of the confines
you had built.
擺脫你築起的牢籠。
WOMAN: to leave,
and so I decided...
...離開，所以我決定...
And free to choose
a path of your own design.
自由地選擇一條你自己設計的路。
(SYNTHPOP MUSIC PLAYING
ELSEWHERE IN THE HOUSE)
(BACKGROUND OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
MARY: (SIGHS)
(MUSIC AND CHATTER NOW MUFFLED)
(MARY INHALES)
(DISTANT CITY HUM)
(LIGHTS FLICKERING)
(CAR PASSING BY)
MAN (ON TV): Well, hey there,
cowboys and cowgirls!
嘿，各位牛仔們！
Are you looking
to rustle up the best deals
你們想找到格蘭德河這邊
this side of the Rio Grande?
最划算的交易嗎？
(HUFFING): Prick.
混蛋。
Well, yeehaw, I say yeehaw!
哇呼，我說哇呼！
Here at Big Wayne's,
our dining room sets
在大偉恩傢俱，我們的餐廳組
are gonna make you feel
like you just struck gold.
會讓你覺得像是挖到了金礦。
So don't even think
about going anyplace else.
所以別想去其他任何地方。
Big Wayne's,
just look for the golden...
大偉恩傢俱，認明金色的——
(SOFT STATIC)
(STATIC GROWS LOUDER)
(TV CLICKS OFF)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
What the...
搞什麼...
(LIGHTS FLICKER)
Stupid... Fuck! Piece of shit!
愚蠢的... 媽的！垃圾東西！
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(HUFFS)
(WEIRD BREAKER CLICKING)
(SIGHS)
(EERIE BUZZING)
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
(SHALLOW BREATHING)
(DEEPER BREATHING)
(DISTANT ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(EERIE SWOOSH)
(GASPS)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(MUMBLES INCOHERENTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(EXHALES LOUDLY)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(FLOOR CREAKING)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(DISTANT RECORDED VOICES FROM
GREETING IN 55 LANGUAGES )
FEMALE VOICE IN CANTONESE:
Gok wai hou maa?
[粵語] 各位好嗎？
Zuk gok wai ping on gin
Hong faai lok.
[粵語] 祝各位平安健康快樂。
(GASPS)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN AKKADIAN)
FEMALE VOICE IN RUSSIAN:
Zdrávstvuyte! Privétstvuyu Vas!
[俄語] 大家好！歡迎你們！
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING IN THAI)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN ARABIC)
IN ARABIC CONTINUES)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN ROMANIAN)
FEMALE VOICE IN FRENCH:
Bonjour tout le monde.
[法語] 大家好。
FEMALE VOICE IN BURMESE:
Naykaungg parsalarr?
[緬甸語] 你們好嗎？
MALE VOICE IN HEBREW: Shalom.
[希伯來語] 平安。
MALE VOICE IN SPANISH:
Hola y saludos a todos.
[西班牙語] 大家好。
MALE VOICE IN INDONESIAN:
Selamat malam hadirin sekalian,
[印尼語] 各位晚安，
selamat berpisah...
[印尼語] 再見...
Hello?
喂？
Dilain waktu.
[印尼語] ...後會有期。
MALE VOICE IN QUECHUA:
Kay pachamamta niytapas may tap as
[克丘亞語] 這句來自地球的問候，
rimapallasta runasimipi.
[克丘亞語] 獻給宇宙的每個角落。
MALE VOICE IN PUNJABI:
Aao ji, jee aya nu.
[旁遮普語] 歡迎。
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN HITTITE)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN BENGALI)
MALE VOICE IN LATIN:
Salvete quicumque estis;
[拉丁語] 歡迎你們，無論你們是誰；
bonam erga
vos voluntatem habemus,
[拉丁語] 我們對你們懷抱善意，
et pacem per astra ferimus.
[拉丁語] 並帶著和平穿越星空。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN ARAMAIC)
FEMALE VOICE IN DUTCH:
Hartelijke groeten aan iedereen.
[荷蘭語] 向大家致以誠摯的問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN GERMAN:
Herzliche Grüße an alle.
[德語] 向大家致以誠摯的問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN URDU:
Assalamu alaikum.
[阿拉伯語] 願和平降臨於你。
Hum zameen ke rehne
waalon ki taraf se
[烏爾都語] 我們地球人
aap ko khush aamdeed kehte hain.
[烏爾都語] 在此歡迎你們。
What the fuck?
搞什麼鬼？
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN VIETNAMESE)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN TURKISH)
FEMALE VOICE IN JAPANESE:
Konnichiwa. O genki desu ka?
[日語] 你好，你好嗎？
MALE VOICE IN HINDI:
Dharati ke waasiyon ki
[印地語] 代表地球居民
or se namaskar.
[印地語] 向你們致敬。
MALE VOICE IN WELSH:
Lechyd da I chi yn awr,
[威爾斯語] 祝你們現在
ac yn oesoedd.
[威爾斯語] 與永遠健康。
FEMALE VOICE IN ITALIAN:
Tanti auguri e saluti.
[義大利語] 最好的祝願和問候。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN SINHALA)
MALE VOICE IN ZULU:
Siya nibingelela maqhawe
[祖魯語] 偉大的勇士們，我們向你們致敬，
sinifisela inkonzo ende.
[祖魯語] 祝你們長壽。
MALE VOICE IN SOTHO:
Reani lumelisa marela.
[索托語] 我們向你們致敬。
FEMALE VOICE IN WU:
Tsoh na da ka hoa.
[納瓦霍語] 大家好。
FEMALE VOICE IN ARMENIAN:
Bolor anonts' vor ky gtnuin
[亞美尼亞語] 向宇宙中
tiezergi migamatsut'iwnen and in,
[亞美尼亞語] 存在的所有事物
voghjoynner.
[亞美尼亞語] 致以問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN KOREAN:
Annyeong haseyo.
[韓語] 你好。
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN POLISH)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN NEPALI)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN MANDARIN)
MALE VOICE IN ILA:
Mypone kaboutu noose.
[伊拉語] 祝大家一切順利。
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN SWEDISH)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
MALE VOICE IN NYANJA:
Mulibwanji imwe boonse
[尼揚賈語] 天上的子民，
bantu bakumwamba.
[尼揚賈語] 你們好嗎。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN GUJARATI)
IN GUJARATI CONTINUES)
MALE VOICE IN UKRAINIAN:
Peresylayemo pryvit
[烏克蘭語] 我們從我們的世界
iz nashoho svitu,
[烏克蘭語] 發送問候，
bazhayemo shchastya,
zdorov'ya I mnohaya lita.
[烏克蘭語] 祝幸福、健康、長壽。
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN PERSIAN)
(GRUNTS)
(CREAKING)
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
(HATCH CRACKS)
(HATCH CREAKS)
(MUFFLED MALE VOICE
SPEAKING IN SERBIAN)
(CLEARER MALE VOICE
SPEAKING IN ORIYA)
MALE VOICE IN GANDA:
Musulayo mutya abantu
[盧干達語] 宇宙的人們你們好，
bensi eno mukama
abawe emirembe bulijo.
[盧干達語] 願上帝永遠賜予你們和平。
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN MARATHI)
(ZIPPER OPENS)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN MARATHI CONTINUES)
FEMALE VOICE IN AMOY:
Thài-khong pêng-iú, lín-hó.
[台語] 太空朋友，恁好。
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN AMOY CONTINUES)
IN HUNGARIAN)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN TELUGU)
Hello?
喂？
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN CZECH)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN KANNADA)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN RAJASTHANI)
(HEAD THUDS) (GROANS)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN RAJASTHANI CONTINUES)
MALE CHILD VOICE: Hello from
the children of Planet Earth.
[英語] 來自地球孩子們的問候。
(DISTANT MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN SUMERIAN)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
MALE VOICE IN ANCIENT GREEK:
Hoitines pot'este chairete!
[古希臘語] 無論你們是誰，大家好！
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN ANCIENT GREEK CONTINUES)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
FEMALE VOICE IN PORTUGUESE:
Paz e felicidade a todos.
[葡萄牙語] 祝大家和平幸福。
FEMALE VOICE in Cantonese:
Gok wai hou maa? Zuk gok wai...
女聲粵語：各位好嗎？祝各位...
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN AKKADIAN)
Ooh...
噢...
FAINT MALE VOICE IN QUECHUA:
Kay pachamamta niytapas
[克丘亞語] 這句來自地球的問候，
may tap as rimapallasta
runasimipi.
[克丘亞語] 獻給宇宙的每個角落。
MALE VOICE IN PUNJABI:
Aao ji, jee aya nu.
[旁遮普語] 歡迎。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN HITTITE)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN BENGALI)
MALE VOICE IN LATIN:
Salvete quicumque estis;
[拉丁語] 歡迎你們，無論你們是誰；
bonam erga vos voluntatem
habemus,
[拉丁語] 我們對你們懷抱善意，
et pacem per astra ferimus.
[拉丁語] 並帶著和平穿越星空。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN ARAMAIC)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
FEMALE VOICE IN DUTCH:
Hartelijke groeten aan iedereen.
[荷蘭語] 向大家致以誠摯的問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN GERMAN:
Herzliche Grüße an alle.
[德語] 向大家致以誠摯的問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN URDU:
Assalamu alaikum.
[阿拉伯語] 願和平降臨於你。
Hum zameen ke rehne waalon ki
[烏爾都語] 我們地球人
taraf se aap ko khush
aamdeed kehte hain.
[烏爾都語] 在此歡迎你們。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN VIETNAMESE)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN TURKISH)
FEMALE VOICE IN JAPANESE:
Konnichiwa. O genki desu ka?
[日語] 你好，你好嗎？
MALE VOICE IN HINDI: Dharati
ke waasiyon ki or se namaskar.
[印地語] 代表地球居民向你們致敬。
MALE VOICE IN WELSH: Lechyd
da I chi yn awr, ac yn oesoedd.
[威爾斯語] 祝你們現在與永遠健康。
FEMALE VOICE IN ITALIAN:
Tanti auguri e saluti.
[義大利語] 最好的祝願和問候。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN SINHALA)
MALE VOICE IN ZULU: Siya
nibingelela maqhawe sinifisela
[祖魯語] 偉大的勇士們，我們向你們致敬，
inkonzo ende.
[祖魯語] 祝你們長壽。
MALE VOICE IN SOTHO:
Reani lumelisa marela.
[索托語] 我們向你們致敬。
(LOUD THUD IN THE DISTANCE)
FEMALE VOICE IN WU: Tsoh na
da ka hoa. Tsoh na da ka hoa.
[納瓦霍語] 大家好。大家好。
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
FEMALE VOICE (in Armenian):
Bolor anonts' vor ky gtnuin
女聲：[亞美尼亞語] 向宇宙中
tiezergi migamatsut'iwnen and in,
[亞美尼亞語] 存在的所有事物
voghjoynner.
[亞美尼亞語] 致以問候。
FEMALE VOICE (in Korean):
Annyeong haseyo.
女聲：[韓語] 你好。
-(FEMALE VOICE, IN POLISH)
-(RHYTHMIC THUDDING CONTINUES)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN NEPALI
GROWING LOUDER)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN MANDARIN)
MALE VOICE IN ILA:
Mypone kaboutu noose.
[伊拉語] 祝大家一切順利。
FEMALE VOICE IN SWEDISH:
Hälsningar från
[瑞典語] 來自
en data programmer are
I den lilla universitetsstaden.
[瑞典語] 地球伊薩卡大學城
Ithaca på plane ten Jorden.
[瑞典語] 一名電腦程式設計師的問候。
MALE VOICE IN NYANJA:
Mulibwanji imwe boonse bantu...
[尼揚賈語] 天上的子民，你們好...
Anyone there?
有人在嗎？
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN GUJARATI)
-(VOICE STOPS ABRUPTLY)
-(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(DISTANT, SLOW CREAK)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(LOUD CRASH)
(CLATTER)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HEAVY THUDS)
(YELPS)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(GRUNTING)
-(RATTLING)
-(CLARK GROANS)
-(HEAVY THUD)
-(DOORKNOBS RATTLE)
Oh, fuck...
噢，媽的...
(SIGH OF RELIEF)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, Okay...
好，好...
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANICKED BREATHING)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(EERIE SWOOSH)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANICKED BREATHING)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(SWALLOWS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING SLOWS DOWN)
FEMALE VOICE IN FRENCH:
Bonjour tout le monde.
[法語] 大家好。
FEMALE VOICE IN BURMESE:
Naykaungg parsalarr?
[緬甸語] 你們好嗎？
MALE VOICE IN HEBREW: Shalom.
[希伯來語] 平安。
MALE VOICE IN SPANISH:
Hola y saludos a todos.
[西班牙語] 大家好。
MALE VOICE IN INDONESIAN:
Selamat malam hadirin sekalian,
[印尼語] 各位晚安，
selamat berpisah dan sampai
bertemu lagi dilain waktu.
[印尼語] 再見，後會有期。
MALE VOICE IN QUECHUA:
Kay pachamamta
[克丘亞語] 這句來自地球的問候，
niytapas may tap as
rimapallasta runasimipi.
[克丘亞語] 獻給宇宙的每個角落。
MALE VOICE IN PUNJABI:
Aao ji, jee aya nu.
[旁遮普語] 歡迎。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN HITTITE)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN BENGALI)
MALE VOICE IN LATIN:
Salvete quicumque estis;
[拉丁語] 歡迎你們，無論你們是誰；
bonam erga
vos voluntatem habemus,
[拉丁語] 我們對你們懷抱善意，
et pacem per astra ferimus.
[拉丁語] 並帶著和平穿越星空。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN ARAMAIC)
FEMALE VOICE IN DUTCH:
Hartelijke groeten aan iedereen.
[荷蘭語] 向大家致以誠摯的問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN GERMAN:
Herzliche Grüße an alle.
[德語] 向大家致以誠摯的問候。
FEMALE VOICE IN URDU:
Assalamu alaikum.
[阿拉伯語] 願和平降臨於你。
Hum zameen ke rehne waalon ki
[烏爾都語] 我們地球人
taraf se aap ko khush
aamdeed kehte hain.
[烏爾都語] 在此歡迎你們。
(DISTANT CITY HUM)
(BIRDS CALLS)
CLARK: Sorry I'm late.
抱歉我遲到了。
(CLARK SIGHS)
Traffic was hell,
and I couldn't leave early.
交通一團糟，而且我沒辦法提早離開。
Let's just use the time we have.
我們就善用剩下的時間吧。
(CLARK BREATHING DEEPLY)
How are you today, Clark?
你今天好嗎，克拉克？
(LAUGHING): How do I look?
妳看我怎麼樣？
Fine. A little tired, maybe.
還好。也許有點累。
I look like shit.
我看起像坨屎。
MARY: Can I ask, and there is
我能問一下嗎，這沒有
no wrong answer here,
you know that...
錯誤的答案，你知道的...
Are you intoxicated right now?
你現在是不是喝醉了？
Why you say it like that?
妳為什麼這麼說？
Like what?
怎麼說？
I haven't had a drink
since Friday.
我從星期五之後就沒喝過酒了。
It's probably why
I look like shit.
這可能就是我看起像坨屎的原因。
(CLEARS THROAT)
-Can I ask you something?
-Sure.
- 我能問妳件事嗎？
- 當然。
You ever 5150'd someone?
妳有對誰執行過 5150 強制送醫嗎？
A few times over the years,
when it was necessary.
這些年來有過幾次，在必要的時候。
Wh-what? -what makes it
necessary?
什-什麼情況下是必要的？
If I believe that the person
is a danger
如果我認為這個人對他們自己
to themselves or others,
或他人構成危險，
or they're gravely disabled.
或是他們嚴重喪失生活自理能力。
Okay. Okay.
好。好。
Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
嗯...
I found something in the store.
我在店裡發現了一些東西。
Okay. What did you find?
好的。你發現了什麼？
Uh...
呃...
A place. I f...
一個地方。我發...
I found a place.
我發現了一個地方。
A place?
一個地方？
Yeah. It's like, um...
對。就像，嗯...
It's like the store just, uh...
就像那間店，呃...
continues, I guess.
無限延伸下去，我猜。
(CHUCKLING): It's like...
you know, like there's a wall
就像是... 妳知道的，像那裡有一道牆
and on the other side
of the wall,
而在牆的另一邊，
the store just keeps going,
you know,
那間店就繼續延伸，妳知道嗎，
like-like a...
like a copy of itself.
像-像是一個... 它自己的複製品。
I-I-I figure they're using
mirrors or something
我-我-我猜他們是用鏡子之類的
to hide the entrance,
I don't know.
來隱藏入口，我不知道。
Sorry, I'm not following you.
抱歉，我聽不太懂。
Is this a room
you didn't know about before?
這是一個你以前不知道的房間嗎？
No.
不是。
Okay, so y-y-you go in
and, uh, at first
好吧，所以你-你-你走進去，呃，一開始
it just looks like a-
like an office building.
它看起來就像一棟- 像一棟辦公大樓。
Like a... like a huge
office building, you know?
像一棟... 像一棟巨大的辦公大樓，懂嗎？
And then, uh...
But then you-you keep going,
然後，呃... 但當你-你繼續走，
and then-then you realize
然後-然後你會意識到
th-th-that none of it
makes any sense.
那-那-那裡的一切都不合常理。
It's-it's like, um...
Imagine describing a dog
它-它就像，嗯... 想像一下向一個
從沒見過狗的人
to someone
who's never seen one before
描述一隻狗
and then asking them to draw it.
然後叫他們畫出來。
They might get
some things right, you know,
他們可能會畫對一些地方，妳懂吧，
but there's no way
they'd get everything right.
但他們不可能把所有細節都畫對。
You know,
the devil's in the details.
妳知道的，魔鬼藏在細節裡。
So from a distance,
you look at it,
所以從遠處看，
you think you're seeing a dog,
but then you look clos...
你以為你看到了一隻狗，但當你湊近看——
Why are you
looking at me like that?
妳為什麼那樣看著我？
I'm just trying to understand.
我只是想理解。
CLARK: Oh.
噢。
You know, for a shrink,
you got a terrible poker face.
妳知道嗎，作為一個心理醫生，
妳完全藏不住表情。
What you're saying
might sound fantastical,
你說的話可能聽起來很不可思議，
but not dangerous.
但並不危險。
Are there any people
in these offices?
那些辦公室裡有人嗎？
Not that I've seen.
You know, I hear, um...
據我所見是沒有。妳知道的，我會聽到，嗯...
There's footsteps, an-an-and
stuff gets moved around
有腳步聲，而且-而且-而且東西會
when I'm not looking.
在我沒看見的時候被移動。
I know how this sounds,
but you've got to understand,
我知道這聽起來很扯，但妳得了解，
it's massive in there.
裡面非常巨大。
Like New-York's-subway-system
massive, you know.
像紐約地鐵系統那樣巨大，妳懂嗎。
For all I know,
there's hundreds of people.
就我所知，裡面可能有幾百人。
I just haven't seen them.
(CLEARS THROAT)
我只是還沒看到他們。
CLARK: Look.
看。
You see? It's like a...
妳看見了嗎？這就像是一個...
(CHUCKLES) It's like a maze.
就像一個迷宮。
It just goes on and on and on.
(LAUGHS)
它就是不斷地延伸下去。
Sometimes I'm scared
I'll get lost.
有時候我很怕自己會迷路。
Why do you think no one else
has found this place?
你覺得為什麼沒有其他人發現這個地方？
(SIGHS) I don't know.
我不知道。
The entrance is on the subfloor,
入口在下層地板那裡，
so the whole structure is
所以整個建築結構
probably underground, you know?
可能都是在地下，妳懂嗎？
It's not on any city maps.
城市地圖上也沒有標示。
The entrances are hidden,
so who'd think to look?
入口被隱藏起來了，所以誰會想到去找？
I'm not saying
I don't believe you...
我不是說
我不相信你...
but you told me yourself
但你自己告訴過我
you haven't had a drink
since Friday.
你從星期五之後
就沒喝過酒了。
-Do you think there is a...
-Okay.
- 你覺得有沒有一種——
- 好吧。
-Clark...
-No, no.
- 克拉克——
- 不，不。
-If this is true...
-Yeah, I get it. Thank you.
- 如果這是真的——
- 對，我懂了。謝謝妳。
(PAPER RUMPLES)
You know, I'm gonna
come back here with proof
妳知道嗎，我會
帶著證據回到這裡
and you're gonna owe me
a serious fucking apology.
然後妳必須
鄭重地他媽的向我道歉。
(OFFICE DOOR OPENS)
(MARY EXHALES)
(RETREATING FOOTSTEPS)
(FRONT DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(ENGINE STARTS OUTSIDE)
(CAR DRIVES AWAY)
(EXHALES)
(SHORT SIGH)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SIGHS)
(WHISPERS TO HIMSELF)
Kat!
凱特！
BOBBY: Jesus, goddamn,
I'm coming! I'm coming!
天啊，該死，
我來了！我來了！
-CLARK: Hey.
-Cap'n Clark?
- 嘿。
- 克拉克船長？
-CLARK: Um...
-Wait, wait, wait, wait. Kat?
- 嗯...
- 等等，等等，等等，等等。凱特？
-KAT: I'm coming.
-Kat!
- 我來了。
- 凱特！
-KAT: Okay, I'm coming!
-(BOBBY SIGHS)
好，我來了！
-CLARK: Look...
-KAT: What the fuck?
- 聽著——
- 搞什麼鬼？
CLARK: Yeah, I'm sorry, uh...
對，抱歉，呃...
What are you guys doing
tomorrow?
你們明天
要做什麼？
KAT: What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
CLARK: I'll pay you.
Two hours. Overtime. Tops.
我會付錢給你們。
兩個小時。算加班。最多兩小時。
Okay, pay us for what?
好，付錢讓我們做什麼？
(FALTERS) Research.
研究。
CLARK:
You got the camera, right?
你帶了攝影機，對吧？
You can-you can
borrow it again...
你可以-你可以
再借用一次...
CLARK: Right?
對吧？
(HISSING FROM ANALOG AUDIO)
(CLARK'S FOOTSTEPS)
(BAG RUSTLING)
BOBBY: Okay, we are rolling.
好，我們開始錄了。
We got, um, some shit over here.
我們這邊，嗯，有些東西。
We got some stop signs
我們有一些停車標誌
and, uh... a rope.
還有，呃... 一條繩子。
What's the rope for?
繩子是做什麼用的？
Supplies.
裝備。
KAT: Oh, great,
he's gonna tie us up.
噢，太好了，他要把我們綁起來。
No, we're gonna tie
ourselves up.
不，我們要把
我們自己綁起來。
BOBBY: Hmm. Kinky.
哼。真變態。
KAT: What the fuck?
搞什麼鬼？
BOBBY:
Uh, you still haven't told us
呃，你還是沒告訴我們
what we're doing here, man.
我們在這裡做什麼，老兄。
I did tell you. Research.
我告訴過你們了。研究。
These are supplies, and we're
using them for research.
這些是裝備，我們要
用它們來做研究。
It's not that hard
to understand.
這又不難理解。
BOBBY: Okay, research for what?
好，研究什麼？
Y-you gotta be
more specific, dude.
你-你得
說得更具體一點，老兄。
I'm gonna go through the door.
我要穿過這扇門。
KAT: What door?
什麼門？
-That's the door.
-(BOBBY SNORTS)
這就是那扇門。
I taped an outline
on the other side, too,
我在另一邊也
用膠帶貼了個輪廓，
just to help us find
our way back.
只是為了幫我們
找到回來的路。
-KAT: Bobby?
-BOBBY (CHUCKLING): What?
- 鮑比？
- 幹嘛？
Look, I know it sounds crazy,
but follow my lead.
聽著，我知道這聽起來很瘋狂，
但跟著我就對了。
-Okay?
-(BOBBY EXHALES LOUDLY)
好嗎？
I want to be back before sunup.
我想在日出前回來。
BOBBY: Dude, it's like 9 p.m.
What the fuck are you talk...
老兄，現在才晚上九點。
你他媽在說什麼——
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(BOBBY GASPS)
-KAT: What the fuck! Clark?!
-BOBBY: What the fuck?
- 搞什麼鬼！克拉克？！
- 搞什麼鬼？
-KAT: How did you do that?
-BOBBY: Dude, did you...
- 你是怎麼做到的？
- 老兄，你有沒有...
Did you fucking see that?!
H-how did he, um...
你他媽看到了嗎？！
他-他是怎麼，嗯...
CLARK: I'm right here.
Come see for yourself.
我就在這裡。
自己過來看。
BOBBY: What the fuck?
D-did you just fucking...
搞什麼鬼？
你-你他媽剛才...
What? How the f...
什麼？這他媽怎麼...
KAT: Bobby, stop.
What are you doing?
鮑比，停下來。
你在做什麼？
-BOBBY: What the fuck?!
-KAT: Clark, where are you?
- 搞什麼鬼？！
- 克拉克，你在哪？
BOBBY: Ha! Hey, did you...
did you see that?
哈！嘿，你有...
你看到了嗎？
-Where the fuck did he go?
-KAT: Yes, Bobby, I saw it!
- 他他媽跑到哪裡去了？
- 對，鮑比，我看到了！
BOBBY: Oh! Where the f...
噢！這他媽——
CLARK: Just step through
the door, you'll be fine!
跨過這扇門過來，
你們會沒事的！
KAT: What?! No!
Tell us what is going on!
什麼？！不！
告訴我們到底發生了什麼事！
-BOBBY: You know what, just...
-(AUDIO CRACKLING)
妳知道嗎，就...
KAT: No, Bobby, wait! Bobby!
Wait, what are you doing?
不，鮑比，等等！鮑比！
等等，你在做什麼？
KAT (VOICE DISTORTED): Bobby!
凱特：鮑比！
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
BOBBY: What the fuck?!
(SURPRISED LAUGH)
搞什麼鬼？！
Dude!
老兄！
Dude, how is this possible?
老兄，這怎麼可能？
-KAT: Bobby! Clark!
-BOBBY: Okay...
- 鮑比！克拉克！
- 好...
KAT: Where are you?
What the fuck is back there?
你在哪裡？
那後面他媽的是什麼？
BOBBY: No, no, no, Kat,
it's good, it's good.
不，不，不，凱特，
沒事，沒事。
J-just, you gotta come see this.
就-就，妳得過來看看這個。
(EERIE SWOOSH)
(BOBBY EXHALES SHARPLY)
I mean... Right, you see...
我是說... 對，妳看...
-You see, it's, um...
-(KAT BREATHES HEAVILY)
妳看，這，嗯...
-BOBBY: It's fine.
-Clark, what is this?
- 沒事的。
- 克拉克，這是什麼？
-Where are we?
-CLARK: Oh!
- 我們在哪？
- 噢！
That's what I'm trying
to figure out.
這正是我試著
弄清楚的事。
BOBBY: Whose, um...
Whose shit is this?
這是誰的，嗯...
這是誰的鬼東西？
Is it-is it...
is it part of your store?
這-這是...
這是你店裡的一部分嗎？
CLARK: If it belongs to someone,
如果它是屬於某人的，
-I haven't met them yet.
-BOBBY: Okay...
- 我還沒遇到他們。
- 好吧...
I've been in here every night
since I found the place,
自從我發現這個地方，我每天晚上都來，
and I still barely scratched
the surface.
卻還只探索了
冰山一角。
-(BOBBY EXHALES DEEPLY)
-Come on. I'll show you.
來吧。我帶你們看。
It only gets better.
後面只會更精彩。
-BOBBY: What the fuck...
-KAT: Hey. Hey.
- 搞什麼鬼...
- 嘿。嘿。
You don't think he, like,
dosed us or something, do you?
妳不覺得他，像是，
給我們下藥了什麼的吧？
What? No, no, no.
We're not on drugs.
什麼？不，不，不。
我們沒吸毒。
I think I'd be able to tell
if I was high.
我想如果我嗑藥了
我自己分辨得出來。
You are high!
你就是有嗑藥！
Pot doesn't count.
大麻不算。
BOBBY: So, um, it's like...
所以，嗯，這就像...
what, like an empty
office building?
什麼，像一棟空蕩蕩的
辦公大樓？
In here? Sure.
But it's like it was made
這裡嗎？沒錯。
但它就像是一群
by a bunch of construction
workers on acid.
嗑了迷幻藥的建築工人
蓋出來的。
(LAUGHING): There's even a pool!
這裡甚至還有個游泳池！
There's a pool?
這裡有游泳池？
Yeah. I mean, kind of.
對。我是說，算是吧。
-(BOBBY CHUCKLES)
-Keep up.
跟上。
BOBBY: "Pots." What the fuck?
「盆子」。搞什麼鬼？
(BOBBY EXHALES DEEPLY)
CLARK: Yeah, no, no, that's
the way I went last time.
對，不，不，那是我
上次走的路。
Yeah, when I was looking for
a staircase down or something.
對，當時我在找
向下的樓梯之類的東西。
Only thing I found so far
is basically more of a...
目前我找到的唯一東西
基本上比較像是一個...
BOBBY: Okay...
好吧...
CLARK: I don't know,
it's like a ramp, really.
我不知道，
它就像個斜坡之類的。
It's, uh... It's up here.
它，呃... 就在這上面。
(BOBBY WHISTLES, SNIFFS)
CLARK: We'll be at it
in a minute.
我們一分鐘後就會到。
-(CAMERA THUDS)
-BOBBY: Okay...
好...
(FAINT WHIR FROM
THE CAMERA ZOOMING IN)
(BOBBY EXHALES SHARPLY)
KAT: How many floors
does it go down?
它往下延伸了幾層樓？
Is this not technically...
從技術上來說這難道不是...
CLARK: Okay.
All right, you filming?
好。
好了，你在錄影嗎？
-BOBBY: Yeah.
-CLARK: All right.
- 有。
- 好。
KAT: I don't see why Bobby
has to be the one to go.
我不懂為什麼
非得是鮑比下去。
-BOBBY: I want to.
-He's the one with the camera.
- 我想去。
- 拿著攝影機的是他。
KAT: Well, it's not
like it's attached.
可是，它又不是
黏在他身上。
BOBBY: Yeah, well, I mean,
對，嗯，我的意思是，
to my student ID,
yeah, it kinda is.
它是用我的學生證借的，
對，所以算是。
Any trouble, just give a tug,
and I'll pull you up, okay?
遇到任何麻煩，扯一下繩子，
我就把你拉上來，好嗎？
KAT: Trouble?
Clark, what fucking trouble?
麻煩？
克拉克，會有什麼他媽的麻煩？
There's not going to be
any trouble.
不會有
任何麻煩的。
BOBBY:
Babe, babe, babe, it's good.
寶貝，寶貝，寶貝，沒事的。
- 不，嘿——
- 沒事的。我沒事。
-No, hey...
-It's good. I'm good.
Baby, you don't have to do this.
寶貝，你不必這麼做。
No, it's cool. I-I just want
to see what's down there.
不，酷斃了。我-我只是想
看看下面有什麼。
-Are you not curious?
-KAT: This is stupid!
- 難道妳不好奇嗎？
- 這太蠢了！
-Just go as far as you can.
-BOBBY: No, look, look, look!
- 能走多遠就走多遠。
- 不，看，看，看！
You can basically
walk down without a rope.
其實你根本不需要
繩子也能走下去。
It's fine,
and it's not even steep.
沒問題的，
而且一點都不陡。
(CLARK GRUNTS) Okay.
好吧。
BOBBY: Okay, just don't...
just one thing.
好吧，只是別...
只有一件事。
If I don't come back, you'll
tell my mom I love her, right?
如果我沒回來，妳要
告訴我媽我愛她，好嗎？
-(KAT BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(BOBBY CHUCKLES)
-CLARK: Okay.
-BOBBY: All right, okay.
- 好。
- 好的，好。
CLARK:
All right, just take it slow.
好的，慢慢來就好。
-CLARK: Okay.
-(BOBBY BREATHING HEAVILY)
好。
BOBBY: Oh, it is
actually kind of steep.
噢，其實
還挺陡的。
-You good?
-BOBBY: Yeah.
- 你還好嗎？
- 嗯。
-Just, uh... try not to drop me.
-All right.
- 只是，呃... 盡量別把我摔了。
- 好。
CLARK: Tell me
how much you need.
告訴我你需要放多少繩子。
(BOBBY BREATHING LOUDLY)
(UNSTEADY FOOTSTEPS)
BOBBY: Whoa... Careful!
哇... 小心！
-(BUMPING)
-(BOBBY GASPS)
What the... Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Fuck! Aah...
搞什麼... 哇！哇！哇！
媽的！啊...
What the fuck
are you guys doing up there?
你們在上面
他媽的在幹嘛？
CLARK: Sorry, sorry!
抱歉，抱歉！
It was stuck
around the leg of the bed!
繩子卡在
床腳上了！
-KAT: Are you okay?
-BOBBY: Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你還好嗎？
- 沒事。對，我沒事。
(MUTTERING):
Jesus fucking Christ...
天啊...
Just keep letting me down!
繼續把我放下去就好！
CLARK: All right. Here we go.
好的。我們繼續。
(CAUTIOUS FOOTSTEPS)
BOBBY: Okay, I'm in.
好了，我到了。
(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
CLARK: See anything?
看到什麼了嗎？
BOBBY: Ugh...
呃...
Uh, it's just...
呃，只有...
It's a bunch of laundry
and shit.
有一堆髒衣服
狗屎垃圾。
CLARK: What do you mean?
Clothes?
什麼意思？
衣服？
BOBBY: Yeah, it just
fucking stinks down here.
對，下面
他媽的臭死了。
CLARK: See anything else?
還有看到別的嗎？
BOBBY: Yeah, just, uh...
Just give me a minute.
有，就是，呃...
給我一點時間。
CLARK: Okay.
好。
(BOBBY GROANS IN DISGUST)
(BOBBY TAKES A DEEP BREATH)
Oh, god...
噢，天啊...
(BOBBY SIGHS)
What the fuck?
搞什麼鬼？
KAT: Bobby?
鮑比？
BOBBY: Yeah.
在。
KAT: Just checking
that you're okay.
只是確認一下你沒事。
BOBBY:
Yeah, I'm fine. Just, um...
對，我沒事。只是，嗯...
Okay...
好...
Yeah.
耶。
Okay.
好。
(BOBBY TAKES A DEEP BREATH)
(BOBBY GROANS IN DISGUST)
What the fuck...?
搞什麼鬼...？
(SINISTER MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
(LIGHTS FLICKER)
KAT: Bobby? Come back up!
鮑比？上來！
-I don't like this!
-(ROPE CREAKING)
我不喜歡這個！
BOBBY: Hey! Uh...
Let some more line out!
嘿！呃...
再多放點繩子！
CLARK: I can't!
It's as far as it goes.
沒辦法了！
繩子到底了。
BOBBY: Fuck...
媽的...
-(OMINOUS CREAK)
-(BOBBY GASPS)
(REPEATING): Fuck! Pull me up!
媽的！把我拉上去！
KAT: Bobby! What is it?
鮑比！怎麼了？
-BOBBY (PANTING): Fuck!
-CLARK: What do you see?
- 媽的！
- 你看到了什麼？
KAT: What the fuck is it?
Pull him up!
那他媽的是什麼鬼東西？
把他拉上來！
-CLARK: I am! Jesus Christ!
-BOBBY: Fuck!
- 我在拉！老天啊！
- 媽的！
KAT: Pull harder!
用力拉！
BOBBY: Pull, man! What the fuck!
拉啊，老兄！
搞什麼鬼！
CLARK: It's getting caught
on my feet!
它卡在我的腳上了！
-I can't pull...
-KAT: Fucking pull harder!
- 我拉不——
- 他媽的再用力一點！
-Clark, hurry up!
-(BOBBY PANTING)
克拉克，快點！
KAT: Almost here! Almost here,
babe, just a little more!
快到了！快到了，
寶貝，再一下就好！
-Pull him up!
-CLARK: What did you see?
- 把他拉上來！
- 你看到了什麼？
BOBBY: There's, uh,
there's someone down there.
那邊，呃，
下面有個人。
-We've got you. What?
-Fuck.
- 我們抓住你了。什麼？
- 媽的。
Slow down, just breathe.
Baby, it's okay.
慢點，深呼吸。
寶貝，沒事了。
Just get this shit
off me, man. Fuck. Jesus.
把這鬼東西
從我身上拿開，老兄。媽的。天啊。
-It's okay. It's okay.
-CLARK: What did you see?
- 沒事了。沒事了。
- 你看到了什麼？
-Here. Hey, deep breath.
-What kind of knot is this?
- 來。嘿，深呼吸。
- 這是什麼結？
Deep breath... (KAT SCREAMS)
深呼吸——
-What the fuck?!
-Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 搞什麼鬼？！
- 哇，哇，哇！
-Help us! Clark!
-Hold on!
- 幫我們！克拉克！
- 抓緊！
-CLARK: Okay, okay, okay!
-Help, you fucking asshole!
- 好，好，好！
- 幫忙，你這個他媽的混蛋！
-CLARK: Let me get it!
-BOBBY: Untie me, man!
- 讓我來！
- 幫我解開，老兄！
What the hell
are you doing, Clark?
你到底
在幹嘛，克拉克？
-CLARK: I can't!
-KAT: Hurry, Clark!
- 我沒辦法！
- 快點，克拉克！
-I'm trying, I'm trying!
-BOBBY: FUCK!
- 我在試了，我在試了！
- 媽的！
-(SHOUTING)
-BOBBY: Don't let go!
別放手！
-KAT: Hold on!
-BOBBY: Fuck! Don't let me go!
- 抓緊！
- 媽的！別放開我！
-Don't let me go!
-CLARK: Let me get at...
- 別放開我！
- 讓我來——
-(BOBBY SCREAMING)
-KAT: BOBBY!
鮑比！
BOBBY (SCREAMING): NO! KAT, NO!
鮑比
不！凱特，不！
(KAT CRYING)
-CLARK: Bobby!
-(BOBBY SCREAMING)
鮑比！
KAT: BOBBY!
-(KAT SOBBING)
-CLARK: Bobby!
鮑比！
KAT: What are we doing?
We need to... Clark!
我們在幹嘛？
我們需要... 克拉克！
(KAT SCREAMING)
(CLARK'S AND KAT'S SCREAMS
CUTTING IN AND OUT)
-(CLARK GROANS)
-(CLATTERING TUMBLE)
-(CLARK GRUNTS)
-(SQUELCHING, GROWLING)
KAT: Bobby! No! No! No!
鮑比！不！不！不！
CLARK: Ow... KAT! Kat...
噢... 凱特！凱特...
KAT: Bobby! (SHOUTING)
鮑比！不！
-KAT: Bobby! No!
-(CLARK MOANS)
(POUNDS ON DOOR) KAT: Bobby! No!
CLARK: Kat! (BREATHING HEAVILY)
凱特！
Oh, fuck... (MOANS)
噢，媽的...
-(SHRIEKING)
-(CLARK WHIMPERS)
Oh, no, no, no, no, no! No!
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
噢，不，不，不，不，不！不！
(DOOR CREAKING)
(CLARK WHIMPERING)
(CRACKLING)
(CLARK BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(QUICK FOOTSTEPS)
(LOUD CRASH)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(RELAXING MUSIC PLAYING
LOUDLY IN THE ROOM)
Kat?!
凱特？！
Kat?
凱特？
-(LOUD THUD)
-(GASPS)
-(CLOSER THUD)
(WHIMPERS)
(LOUD SCRAPING)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING
FELIZ NAVIDAD IN THE ROOM)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MUSIC BOX STOPS)
(MUSIC BOX RESUMES)
(CLARK HOLDS HIS BREATH)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hello?
喂？
(MUSIC BOX STOPS)
-(CLARK YELPS)
-(EERIE GROAN)
-(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
-(CLARK GASPS)
(CLARK MUMBLES, PANICKED)
Stay back! Get away from me!
退後！
離我遠一點！
(WHIMPERS)
(LONG EERIE SHRIEK)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(EERIE SHRIEK CONTINUES)
(PANTING)
-(GASPS)
-(WATER SPLASHES)
-(FOOTSTEPS SQUEAKING)
-(MOANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(RUNNING WATER)
-(CRASH IN THE DISTANCE)
-(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(KNOCKING ON THE WALL)
(GASPS)
KAT: Clark? CLARK! I'm here...
克拉克？克拉克！我在這裡...
(KAT KNOCKS AGAIN)
I'm here! It's gonna come back.
我在這裡！
牠會回來的。
Please, Clark, please let me in!
拜託，克拉克，拜託讓我進去！
-Kat?
-KAT: Let me in!
- 凱特？
- 讓我進去！
(KAT SOBBING)
Wh-wh-where are you?
妳-妳-妳在哪？
KAT: We have to go now, Clark!
We have to go.
我們現在得走了，克拉克！
我們得走了。
It's gonna come back,
it's gonna find me!
牠會回來的，
牠會找到我的！
Kat! Kat? Uh... Wait, I don't
understand. Wh-where are you?
凱特！凱特？呃... 等等，我
不明白。妳-妳在哪？
KAT (CRYING):
Please, let me the fuck in!
凱特：拜託，他媽的讓我進去！
(KAT KNOCKING, SOBBING)
But it's a... it's-it's a wall!
可是這是一面...
這-這是一面牆啊！
How can-how can you see me?
妳怎麼能-妳怎麼能看到我？
KAT: I'm on the other side
of the glass.
我在玻璃的另一邊。
-How can you see...?
-KAT: How can you not see me?
- 妳怎麼能看到...？
- 你怎麼可能看不到我？
What glass?! What the fuck
are you talking about?
什麼玻璃？！妳他媽的
在說什麼？
(PANICKED BREATH)
Wh-what are you talk...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
妳-妳在說什——
Okay, can you see anything
on your side?
好，妳能看到
妳那邊有什麼嗎？
Can you see a handle, a door?
Is there a hatch, anything?
妳有看到把手，或門嗎？
有艙門嗎，任何東西？
KAT (SOBBING): No, no, no, no...
凱特：沒有，沒有，沒有，沒有...
Uh... Okay. Let me figure
this out, okay? Just hold on.
呃... 好。讓我想辦法
弄清楚，好嗎？等一下。
Hold on, okay? It's just...
等一下，好嗎？
只是...
(KAT CRYING)
-KAT: Clark?
-No, no, just let me...
- 克拉克？
- 不，不，讓我...
-KAT: Clark!
-Just hold on!
- 克拉克！
- 等一下！
-Let me figure this out!
-KAT: CLARK!
- 讓我想想辦法！
- 克拉克！
-Let me figure this out...
-KAT: Clark! Clark!
- 讓我想想辦法...
- 克拉克！克拉克！
Clark, behind you!
克拉克，你後面！
(KAT HEAVING)
(FLY BUZZING)
(DOG BARKING OUTSIDE)
(CHILDREN'S VOICES OUTSIDE)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING SOFTLY)
(INDISTINCT CHILDREN CHATTER)
(CREAKING)
(PAPER RUSTLES)
(WINDOW HANDLE SQUEAKING)
-Mary!
-(CLACK)
瑪麗！
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
-(EERIE TINKLING)
-(LOW RUMBLE)
(MARY'S MOM INHALES DEEPLY)
Mary...
瑪麗...
what were you thinking?
妳在想什麼？
I never, ever,
我從來，絕對，
ever said you could go outside.
絕對沒有說過妳可以去外面。
It's no good.
那裡不好。
They're all over the place.
他們到處都是。
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
-(MARY'S MOM SIGHS)
-(KNOCKING ON FRONT DOOR)
(CREAKING)
(LOUD CRASH)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(INHALES AND EXHALES DEEPLY)
(PHONE RINGING)
(ANSWERING MACHINE
ACTIVATING SIGNAL)
(GREETING MESSAGE): Hi,
you've reached Dr. Mary Klein.
嗨，
這是瑪麗·克萊恩博士的語音信箱。
I'm not able to answer the call,
我現在無法接聽電話，
so please leave a message,
所以請留言，
and I'll get back to you
as soon as I can.
我會盡快回覆您。
(CRACKLING ON THE LINE)
CLARK (ON ANSWERING MACHINE):
Mary...
克拉克：瑪麗...
(CLARK'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
I opened the window.
我打開了窗戶。
(CLARK'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
I won't be coming back.
我不會回去了。
(END OF MESSAGE SIGNAL)
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
(SEAGULLS CALLING)
(LIQUID SLOSHING AROUND)
(RUSTLE, CLINK)
(BRAKE SQUEAKING)
(ENGINE IDLES)
(POPCORN POPPING)
GIRL (ON TV): Please!
女孩：拜託！
(MICROWAVE BEEPS)
Save us!
救救我們！
BOY (ON TV):
All right! I'll do it!
男孩：
好！我來！
I'll save you! I will do it!
我會救妳！我會做到的！
(BOY ON TV SHOUTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC ON TV)
BOY (ON TV): Don't die!
男孩：不要死！
(BOY ON TV SCREAMING)
I don't know
where that hand's been.
我不知道
那隻手去過哪裡。
(DRAMATIC MUSIC ON TV ENDS)
CAP'N CLARK (ON TV):
Well, ahoy there, mateys!
克拉克船長：
嘿，各位水手們！
Now, according to me map,
現在，根據我的地圖，
we've landed
on the crystal shores
我們已經登陸了
水晶海岸，
of a bountiful land,
來到了一片豐饒的土地，
a land filled with great deals.
一片充滿超值優惠的土地。
So drop your anchors
and come on down
所以拋下你們的錨，
快來
to Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire.
克拉克船長的奧斯曼帝國。
Get lost in an endless sea
迷失在無盡的汪洋中吧，
of quality tables, chairs,
couches, and bedroom sets.
這裡有高品質的桌子、椅子、
沙發和臥室傢俱組。
Need bed bunks
for the scallywagses quarters?
需要雙層床
讓那些小壞蛋們睡覺嗎？
We've got it all!
我們應有盡有！
And at prices so low
而且價格低到
you'll think
that you're robbing me!
你會以為
你在搶劫我！
(INAUDIBLE)
(DISTANT TRAFFIC HUM)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(BOSSA NOVA MUZAK PLAYING
ON STORE'S SPEAKERS)
Hello?
喂？
(FLY BUZZING)
Hello?
喂？
Clark?
克拉克？
(LIGHTS FLICKERING)
Clark, can you hear me?
克拉克，你聽得到嗎？
(LIGHTS FLICKERING)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(BOSSA NOVA MUZAK
PLAYING FROM UPSTAIRS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING SOFTLY)
Clark?
克拉克？
(SHALLOW BREATHING)
(GASPS)
(INAUDIBLE FLASHBACK)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING SOFTLY)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING LOUDER)
(FLY BUZZING)
(BUZZING STOPS ABRUPTLY)
-(GASPS)
-(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(UNKNOWN CREAKING)
-(GASPS)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(DEEP BREATHS)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC RISES)
(BREATHING ANXIOUSLY)
-(EERIE SWOOSH)
-(GASPS)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(FLY BUZZING)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
Clark?
克拉克？
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
(SHALLOW BREATHING)
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(FAINT VOICES IN THE DISTANCE)
(VOICES GETTING LOUDER)
(CLEARER VOICES, OVERLAPPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(TENSE MUSIC TURNS EERIE)
(VOICES FADE OUT)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(CREAKING)
(STARTLING TONE)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Clark?
克拉克？
CLARK: You found it.
妳找到它了。
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
MARY: Why are you hiding?
你為什麼躲起來？
CLARK: You were being too loud.
妳太大聲了。
(CLARK SIGHS)
Where are we?
我們在哪裡？
It's... (DEEP BREATH)
這裡是...
Every place that ever was.
...所有曾經存在過的地方。
(FLIES BUZZING)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
How long have you been here?
你在這裡待多久了？
(HESITATES)
-(LOUD THUD, EERIE GROWL)
-(MARY GASPS)
-(CREAKING)
-What was that?
那是什麼？
(EERIE GROWL, CREAKING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
CLARK: Stay calm.
保持冷靜。
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
It's only me.
只是我而已。
(MARY BREATHING HEAVILY)
You know me.
妳認識我的。
(RHYTHMIC HEAVY THUDS)
(THUDS GETTING LOUDER)
(TENSE MUSIC RISES)
(FLICKERING AND
THUDDING STOP ABRUPTLY)
(LIGHT CLICKING OFF)
(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
-(CLARK GRUNTING)
-(MARY CHOKING)
(MARY'S RASPING BREATH)
(CLARK'S DISTORTED GRUNT)
CLARK (DISTORTED): I'm sorry.
克拉克：對不起。
This is for your own good.
這都是為妳好。
(MARY'S STRENUOUS BREATHING)
(DISTORTED CHIME TINKLES)
(SINISTER MUSIC FADES OUT)
(DISTORTED CHIME TINKLES
FADE OUT)
(1920s SLOW JAZZ MUSIC
WITH VINYL CRACKLING EFFECT)
(WHEELCHAIR CLICKS)
(WHEELCHAIR SQUEAKS)
(JAZZ MUSIC CONTINUES)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING,
OVERLAPPING JAZZ MUSIC)
(JAZZ MUSIC FADES OUT)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(EERIE RUMBLING AND CREAKING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
CLARK (DISTANT VOICE):
As you walk through life,
克拉克：當妳走過人生，
the untrained mind
accumulates loops, habits...
未經訓練的心智會
累積循環、習慣...
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
Behaviors that keep you
drifting in circles,
...讓妳在原地打轉的
行為模式，
creating the same problems,
製造同樣的問題，
reaching for the same solutions
尋求相同的解決方法
over and over again.
一次又一次。
Still, it's the neural pathway
of least resistance.
儘管如此，這仍是阻力最小的
神經傳導路徑。
(MARY'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
(DISTORTED
OLD JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(VOICE CLEAR) The one I made.
我走出來的那條路。
The one that kept me safe...
在我童年時期...
when I was a child.
保護了我的那一條。
(CLEARS THROAT) You know...
妳知道嗎...
(CLARK INHALES DEEPLY)
I learned to push people away
before they could hurt me.
我學會了在別人傷害我之前
先把他們推開。
And, now, as an adult,
而現在，身為一個成年人，
I'm still stuck
right where I started.
我依然困在
最初的起點。
(DEEP SIGH)
Alone.
孤單一人。
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
What is this?
這是什麼？
It's a real mess. Am I right?
這真是一團糟。
對吧？
Clark...
克拉克...
(SWALLOWS HARD)
let me help you...
...讓我幫你...
before you do anything
you can't take back.
在你做出任何
無法挽回的事之前。
Answer the question.
回答問題。
Yes, it's a real mess.
對，這是一團糟。
But also beautiful in a way.
但在某種程度上也很美。
No?
不是嗎？
(DISTORTED
OLD JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Who are these people?
這些人是誰？
This place builds them.
是這個地方建造了他們。
Oh, actually,
more like it remembers them.
噢，其實，
更像是它記住了他們。
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
And the more times
it remembers something,
而它記住某個東西
越多次，
the less it does.
它保留的細節就越少。
Somewhere out there
is a guy in a striped shirt,
在外面的某個地方
有個穿條紋襯衫的傢伙，
but, in here, he's...
但在這裡，他是...
remembered.
被記住的。
Just slightly wrong.
只是有點走樣。
(CLARK SIGHS)
Somewhere out there is a man
在外面的某個地方
有個男人
in a wheelchair, and a lamp.
坐在輪椅上，還有一盞檯燈。
I'm pretty sure that's
how you get all of this.
我很確定這就是
這裡一切的由來。
You know, all these places
妳知道的，所有這些地方
and rooms and buildings
房間和建築
misremembering themselves.
都是對它們自身的錯誤記憶。
Clark...
克拉克...
let's talk this through.
我們把話說清楚。
In some ways...
在某些方面...
they're an improvement
on the originals.
它們比原來的更好。
For starters,
首先，
they can't feel anything.
它們沒有任何感覺。
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
-(UNSETTLING MUSIC RISES)
-(MARY GASPS)
(SQUELCHING NOISES)
(HEAVY, PANICKED BREATHING)
(MARY EXHALES LOUDLY)
Can you imagine
how good that must feel?
妳能想像
那種感覺有多好嗎？
(CLARK LAUGHS)
I mean...
我的意思是...
(MARY LOUDLY EXHALES)
There's no thoughts
or pain, no ego, no fear.
...沒有思想、
沒有痛苦、沒有自我、沒有恐懼。
They simply...
它們只是單純地...
exist.
存在。
Like... like furniture!
就像... 像傢俱一樣！
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Look at this. The best part.
看看這個。
最棒的部分。
-(BUTTONS POPPING)
-(CLARK GRUNTS SOFTLY)
You can eat them!
妳可以把它們吃掉！
(CLARK CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
-(SQUELCHING TEAR)
-(GASPS LOUDLY)
(CLARK GRUNTS)
-(SQUELCHING TEAR)
-(TROUBLED GROAN)
(SQUELCHING TEAR)
-(GOOEY PLOP)
-(MARY GASPS)
(CLARK CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(EXCITED CHUCKLE)
(SURPRISED MUMBLE)
(CLARK'S SUDDEN EXCLAMATION)
(GASPS, SHUDDERING BREATH)
(CLARK SIGHS)
(LABORED BREATHING)
That's my, uh...
那是我的，呃...
assistant manager.
副理。
(LABORED BREATHING) (GRUNTS)
I tried to help her,
but she just, uh...
我試過要幫她，
但她就是，呃...
Clark!
克拉克！
If you untie me,
we can talk this through,
如果你把我解開，
我們可以好好談談，
get you feeling better.
讓你感覺好點。
Yeah, well,
what if I did untie you?
是啊，那，
如果我把妳解開呢？
You know, what then?
妳知道的，然後呢？
You'd run around here
妳會在這裡到處亂跑
like a chicken
with its head cut off,
像隻
被砍了頭的雞一樣，
looking for a way out.
尋找出口。
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
But you'd end up in
the same place you are now.
但妳最終還是會回到
妳現在所在的地方。
(PANTING)
Like the path thing
you're always talking about.
就像妳總是說的
那個關於路徑的理論。
Clark!
克拉克！
I just want to help you.
Just tell me what you need.
我只是想幫你。
告訴我你需要什麼就好。
I'll-I'll-I'll do it.
我-我-我會做到的。
Yeah?
真的嗎？
Yeah. Yes, please.
對。對，拜託。
(DEEP SIGH) Okay.
好。
Well, I want you to tell me
嗯，我要妳告訴我
that I didn't do
anything wrong, you know,
我並沒有做錯
任何事，妳知道嗎，
that-that you were wrong
about me.
那-那都是妳
對我的誤解。
I was wrong about you! I was.
我對你有誤解！我錯了。
-I was wrong about you.
-No, no, not-not like that.
- 我對你有誤解。
- 不，不，不是-不是這樣。
Not... not so fast, okay?
別... 別急，好嗎？
I mean, I wanna...
I want to set the scene first!
我的意思是，我想...
我想先設定一下場景！
(CLARK CHUCKLES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Let's start, um...
我們從，嗯... 開始
well, the night that, uh...
就是那個，呃...
that I got kicked out
of my own house.
我被趕出
我自己房子的那晚。
Yeah?
對吧？
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CLARK SIGHS)
It was, um... It was late.
那時候，嗯... 很晚了。
A lot darker.
而且暗得多。
Uh...
呃...
Lights, please.
關燈，謝謝。
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHUCKLES)
I tried this exercise
with her before.
我以前和她試過
這個練習。
It doesn't go anywhere.
根本毫無進展。
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
(INHALES) Fine!
好吧！
I'll do it myself.
(CLEARS THROAT)
我自己來。
(GRUNTS)
It's still my house after all.
畢竟這還是我的房子。
(SIGHS)
Yeah.
對。
-(MARY GASPS)
-Thank you. Much better.
謝謝。好多了。
But there's...
但還是...
still...
有些...
something off.
不太對勁。
-(SQUELCHING NOISE)
-(SMALL EFFORT GRUNT)
Clark, please...
克拉克，拜託...
(CLARK GRUNTS)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
-(SQUELCHING TEAR)
-(METALLIC SLASH)
(WET SLICING)
(CLARK GRUNTS)
(SLOW RIPPING SOUND)
(CLARK GRUNTS LOUDLY)
-(CLARK SIGHS)
-(MARY GASPS)
No, please, don't, don't...!
不，拜託，不要，不要...！
-(MARY GASPS)
-(CLARK SIGHS)
-(MARY EXHALES SHARPLY)
-(CLARK BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SHALLOW BREATH)
I'm sorry.
對不起。
I'm sorry, I...
對不起，我...
broke the glass and woke you up.
打破了玻璃杯，吵醒了妳。
I know how you like
to sleep early.
我知道妳習慣
早睡。
I was at the store late.
我在店裡待得很晚。
I guess I lost track
of the time.
我想我沒注意
時間。
I was checking inventory.
我在盤點庫存。
But...
但是...
I stopped off for a few beers.
我中途停下來喝了幾杯啤酒。
-Clark...
-Barbara!
- 克拉克——
- 芭芭拉！
I was checking inventory.
我在盤點庫存。
Then I stopped off
for a few beers.
然後我中途停下來
喝了幾杯啤酒。
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Defi-define a few.
幾-幾杯是多少。
As many as I wanted.
我想喝多少就喝多少。
Because this is my house.
因為這是我的房子。
I pay for it.
我付的錢。
I pay for everything.
I pay for you to go to school.
我支付所有開銷。
我付錢讓妳去上學。
I pay for your time off school!
我付妳休學期間的生活費！
I pay for the roof
over your head!
我付我們住的
房子的錢！
You want kids, right?
妳想要孩子，對吧？
Well, that takes money.
嗯，這需要錢。
So someone has to work
around here.
所以家裡總得有人
去工作。
I said someone has
我說總得有人
to get off her fat ass
and work around here!
抬起她那胖屁股
來幫忙工作！
Just because you didn't get
to be an architect don...
只因為你沒能
成為一名建築師並不——
I am a fucking architect.
我就是個他媽的建築師。
(UNSETTLING MUSIC SLOWLY RISES)
I'm just stuck selling
shit furniture because someone
我只是被困在這裡賣
爛傢俱，因為有人
won't get off her fat
fucking ass and help me!
就是不肯抬起她那
他媽的胖屁股來幫我！
-I'm not your wife!
-Stay in character.
- 我不是你老婆！
- 留在角色裡。
-(MARY EXHALES LOUDLY)
-Stay in character!
留在角色裡！
-I've never even met her!
-STAY IN CHARACTER!
- 我根本沒見過她！
- 留在角色裡！
FUCK YOU!
去你的！
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
What did you say?
妳說什麼？
You wanna know the real reason
your wife left you?
你想知道你老婆
離開你的真正原因嗎？
It wasn't the drinking,
不是因為酗酒，
or the stumbling home
at all hours, or the rage.
或是不分晝夜地蹣跚回家，
或是你的暴怒。
It was the whining!
是因為你的牢騷！
Nothing's ever your fault,
is it?
什麼都不是你的錯，
對吧？
You drink too much?
Blame your job.
你喝太多？
怪你的工作。
You hate your job?
Blame the world.
你討厭你的工作？
怪這個世界。
You get kicked out of the house?
你被趕出家門？
Blame your wife.
怪你老婆。
You attack me and tie me up?
你攻擊我還把我綁起來？
Blame your brain!
怪你的大腦！
You are your fucking brain,
you dipshit!
你他媽的就是你的大腦，
你這個蠢蛋！
-You're saying it's my fault?
-Yes!
- 妳是說這是我的錯？
- 沒錯！
But it's just the way
you're wired, isn't it?
但這就是你
天生的樣子，不是嗎？
ISN'T IT?!
不是嗎？！
(INHALES, EXHALES)
How do I stop doing that?
我該怎麼停止這麼做？
Honestly,
I have no fucking idea.
說實話，
我他媽的根本不知道。
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
I can't help you, Clark.
我幫不了你，克拉克。
As much as I tried.
儘管我已經盡力了。
It's just not up to me.
這不是我能決定的。
(DEEP SIGH)
I can't save anyone.
我救不了任何人。
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(CLARK'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
You know...
妳知道嗎...
I don't think I want to change.
我想我不想改變了。
Then don't.
那就別改。
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
I like it in here.
我喜歡這裡面。
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
For the first time
in a long time,
好長一段時間以來，
這是第一次，
I feel like I'm...
我覺得我...
like I'm right where
I'm supposed to be.
覺得我待在
我該待的地方。
(SIGHS)
Then stay.
那就留下來吧。
Right where you are.
就在你現在的地方。
(INHALES SHARPLY) But let me go.
但讓我走。
(PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CLARK SIGHS)
(CLARK SNIFFLES)
(SHALLOW BREATH)
(MARY BREATHING NERVOUSLY)
I'm sorry.
對不起。
(MARY GASPS)
(FAINT RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
About what?
對不起什麼？
(REPEATED THUDDING, SHRIEKING)
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING APPROACHING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(MARY GASPS)
(EERIE GROWL, THUDDING)
-(MARY'S PANICKED BREATHING)
-(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
(THUDDING GETTING LOUDER)
(CREAKING)
What are you doing in here?
妳在這裡面做什麼？
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
(MARY'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
This is Mary.
這是瑪麗。
She's our therapist.
她是我們的心理醫生。
-(MARY'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
-She was just leaving.
她正要離開。
No, no.
不，不。
You don't have to worry.
妳不用擔心。
She says
we don't need to change.
她說
我們不需要改變。
(CREAKING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CLARK'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
It's okay.
沒事的。
It's just the way we're wired.
這只是我們天生的樣子。
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
(RASPY GROAN) (SQUELCHING BITE)
(CLARK SCREAMING)
-(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
-(MARY GASPS)
-(LOW GROWL)
-(CLARK SCREAMING)
-(FRENZIED THUDDING)
(PIRATE'S MENACING GROWL)
(SHOCKED WHIMPERS)
(LOW GROWL)
-(MARY YELPS)
-(CLARK SCREAMING)
(SQUELCHING TEAR)
(MENACING GROWLS)
(CLARK SCREAMING)
(PIRATE CLARK GROWLS LOUDLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SINISTER MUSIC CONTINUES)
(GROWL) (HEAVY THUD)
(PANTING)
-(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
-(PANICKED BREATHING)
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
(CLARK'S BODY THUMP)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING APPROACHING)
(PANTING)
(LIGHT BUZZING FAINTLY)
(MENACING GROWL)
(RUMBLING)
(CRASH IN THE DISTANCE)
(MENACING GROWL)
(LOUD CLINKING)
(GROWLING)
(PANICKED BREATHING)
-(THUD, BONE CRACKS)
-(YELPS)
(MOANING IN PAIN)
(WHIMPERS)
(PANTING)
(SINISTER MUSIC CONTINUES)
(GROWLING)
(LOUD FOOTSTEPS)
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
-(LOCKED DOOR THUMPS)
-(EFFORT GRUNT)
(GROWLS, THUDS, AND BANGING)
-(PIRATE CLARK GRUNTS)
-(MARY YELPS)
(GROWLING)
(MARY PANTING)
(EERIE DREAMY MUSIC
REVERBERATING)
(GROWLING, LOUD BANGING)
(MARY GASPS)
(LOUD BANGING)
(EERIE DREAMY MUSIC
OVERLAPPING SINISTER MUSIC)
(LOUD BANGING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(SPLINTERING CRACK)
(BANGING CONTINUES, GROWLING)
(LOUD GROWL)
(DOOR BREAKS)
(YELPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(AGGRESSIVE BANGING)
-(LOUD CRASH)
-(MENACING GROWLING)
(DISTANT ANGRY GROWLING)
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BREATHING QUICKENS)
(ANGRY GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(GREETINGS IN 55 LANGUAGES,
MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN ORIYA)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
MALE VOICE IN GANDA:
Musulayo mutya abantu bensi eno
[盧干達語] 宇宙的人們你們好，
mukama abawe emirembe bulijo.
[盧干達語] 願上帝永遠賜予你們和平。
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN MARATHI)
IN MARATHI CONTINUES)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING IN AMOY)
FEMALE VOICE IN HUNGARIAN:
Üdvözletet küldünk magyar...
[匈牙利語] 我們用匈牙利語...
-No...
-(FEMALE VOICE CONTINUES)
不...
(HEAVY BREATHING CONTINUES)
(DOOR THUDS)
(EERIE MUSIC TURNS OMINOUS)
(DOOR OPENS, CREAKS THEN SLAMS)
(LOW RASPY BREATH)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN KANNADA)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN RAJASTHANI)
(RASPY GASP)
(PEG LEG CLUNKING)
MALE CHILD VOICE: Hello from
the children of Planet Earth.
[英語] 來自地球孩子們的問候。
(RHYTHMIC CLUNKING APPROACHING)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN SUMERIAN)
(LOW RASPY GROAN)
(MARY'S SHUDDERING BREATH)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN ANCIENT GREEK)
FEMALE VOICE IN PORTUGUESE:
Paz e felicidade a todos.
[葡萄牙語] 祝大家和平幸福。
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN AKKADIAN)
FEMALE VOICE IN RUSSIAN:
Zdrávstvuyte! Privétstvuyu Vas!
[俄語] 大家好！歡迎你們！
(CLUNKING CONTINUES)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING IN THAI)
-(MARY PANTING)
-(FEMALE VOICE, IN ARABIC)
(PIRATE CLARK GROWLING)
-(MARY GASPS)
-(MENACING GROWL)
-(MARY GRUNTS)
-(WOOD CRACKS)
(YOWLS)
FEMALE VOICE IN FRENCH:
Bonjour tout le monde.
[法語] 大家好。
(GASPS, GRUNTS)
-(BEEPING)
-(ALARM BLARES)
(GAS HISSING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC TURNS TENSE)
(PIRATE CLARK YOWLS)
-(MARY WHIMPERS)
-(PIRATE CLARK GROWLING)
(SOUNDSCAPE BECOMES MUFFLED)
(MUFFLED COUGH AND BREATHING)
(MUFFLED GASP)
(MUFFLED GROAN)
(MUFFLED HISSING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(STARTLING TENSE TONE)
-(PIRATE'S RASPY BREATHING)
-(MARY GASPS)
-(GROWLING)
-(MARY INHALES SHARPLY)
(MARY'S STRENUOUS GRUNTS)
(MENACING GROWL)
(HORRIFYING GRUNT)
(MARY'S STRENUOUS GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(TENSE MUSIC RISES)
(GROWLING)
-(HARD BLOW)
-(RASPY WHIMPERS)
-(MARY GRUNTS, PANTS)
-(HARD BLOW)
-(RASPY WHIMPERS)
-(SQUELCHING BLOWS)
-(PIRATE CLARK YOWLING)
-(MARY GRUNTING)
-(REPEATED SQUELCHING BLOWS)
-(PIRATE GROWLING AND YOWLING)
-(HORRIFYING GROANS)
-(MARY'S STRENUOUS YELL)
(JAW CRACKS) (TEETH RATTLE)
-(PIRATE CLARK WHIMPERS)
-(MARY GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(PIRATE CLARK'S GROWL )
-(MARY'S PANICKED BREATHING)
(ANGRY YOWLING)
-(HARD BUMP)
-(MARY GASPS)
-(PIRATE CLARK GROWLING)
-(MARY PANTING)
(WHIMPERING GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(WHIMPERING GROWLS)
(HOWLING)
(DARK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(HOWLING BECOMES FAINTER)
(BREATHING QUICKENS)
(MARY GASPS)
(GAS HISSING)
(DARK MUSIC TURNS TENSE)
(YELPS) (COUGHS)
HAZMAT GUY 1: Are you okay?
妳還好嗎？
HAZMAT GUY 2:
Who the fuck is that?
那他媽的是誰？
HAZMAT GUY 2: Who is it?
是誰？
(MARY COUGHS)
HAZMAT GUY 3: What happened?
發生了什麼事？
(HAZMAT GUYS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(MARY HYPERVENTILATING)
GUY 3: What about the pirate?
Can you still see the pirate?
那個海盜呢？
妳還能看到海盜嗎？
GUY 2: And the other guys?
Still going out the back?
還有其他人呢？
還在往後面走嗎？
(MARY PANTING)
HAZMAT GUYS:
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(TENSE MUSIC FADES OUT)
(MUFFLED BEEPING)
(MUFFLED PANTING)
(MUFFLED BEEPING CONTINUES)
(MUFFLED HEAVY BREATHING)
(MUFFLED RINGING)
(SILENCE)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING OVER
GREETINGS IN 55 LANGUAGES)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN ORIYA)
MALE VOICE IN GANDA:
Musulayo mutya abantu bensi eno
[盧干達語] 宇宙的人們你們好，
mukama abawe emirembe bulijo.
[盧干達語] 願上帝永遠賜予你們和平。
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN MARATHI)
FEMALE VOICE IN AMOY:
Thài-khong pêng-iú, lín-hó.
[台語] 太空朋友，恁好。
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN AMOY CONTINUES)
FEMALE VOICE IN HUNGARIAN:
Üdvözletet küldünk magyar
[匈牙利語] 我們用匈牙利語
nyelven minden békét szeretö
lénynek aVilágegyetemen.
[匈牙利語] 向宇宙中所有愛好和平的
生命致以問候。
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN TELUGU)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING IN CZECH)
(FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN KANNADA)
(MALE VOICE SPEAKING
IN RAJASTHANI)
MALE CHILD VOICE: Hello from
the children of Planet Earth.
[英語] 來自地球孩子們的問候。
(DISTANT BIRD CALLS)
(CAP'N CLARK COMMERCIAL
PLAYING FAINTLY OUTSIDE)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(FOOTSTEPS STOPPING)
Hello, my name is Phil.
妳好，我叫菲爾。
And you're Mary, yeah?
妳是瑪麗，對吧？
Uh... I was hoping to ask you
a few questions, just for...
呃... 我希望能問妳
幾個問題，只是為了...
some clarification on our end,
讓我們這邊能釐清一些事，
if that's okay.
如果可以的話。
Uh, first thing, um...
呃，第一件事，嗯...
could you establish
how you, uh...
妳能確認一下
妳是怎麼，呃...
got in here?
進來這裡的嗎？
I walked through a wall
我穿過了一道牆
in the basement
of a furniture store.
在一家傢俱店的
地下室裡。
Hmm.
嗯。
(PHOTO RUSTLES)
Can you confirm that this is
the location in question?
妳能確認這就是
我們所說的地點嗎？
Okay, good.
So you were shopping, or...
好，很好。
所以妳當時在購物，還是...
I was looking for someone.
我在找人。
-(PHOTO RUSTLES)
-Um...
嗯...
were you looking for this man,
妳是在找這個男人嗎，
right here?
就是這裡的這個？
Where am I right now?
我現在在哪裡？
Could you just confirm for me?
你能跟我確認一下嗎？
Is this man right here
the man you were looking for?
這個男人
就是妳在找的人嗎？
-Please.
-(PHIL STUTTERS)
拜託。
-Sorry, what was your name?
-Phil.
- 抱歉，你叫什麼名字？
- 菲爾。
Please, Phil. Where am I?
拜託，菲爾。我在哪裡？
I'm not...
我不...
(SIGHS)
I make, um... Sorry, my...
我製造，嗯... 抱歉，我的...
Our company, we make...
我們的公司，我們製造...
MRI machines.
MRI 機器。
Or... I should say, um,
或者... 我應該說，嗯，
we used to make MRI machines.
我們曾經製造 MRI 機器。
Not anymore.
現在不了。
That was before we...
那是在我們... 之前的事
(DEEP BREATH)
-Before we found...
-You've been there.
- 在我們發現——
- 你去過那裡。
Yes, I have.
對，我去過。
And now, it's my job. (SIGHS)
而現在，這是我的工作。
Every day, I-I go in there
and I just try to f...
每天，我-我進去那裡
然後我只是試著去發...
try to find out ev-even
a little bit more.
試著去多發現
哪怕只是一點點。
I-I map out areas
to the best of my ability.
我-我盡我所能地
繪製出各個區域的地圖。
And more and more, I'm convinced
我越來越確信
that nothing
in our lifetime, Mary,
在我們有生之年，瑪麗，
沒有任何事物，
n-nothing in-in maybe
all of recorded history
沒-沒有任何事物，在-在或許
所有的歷史記載中
means more than this.
比這更重要了。
But I don't understand it.
I don't...
但我了解它。
我不...
I-I can't even describe it.
我-我甚至無法描述它。
It...
它...
It's like describing a dog
就像是向一個
to someone
who's never seen a dog.
從沒見過狗的人描述一隻狗。
And then asking them to draw it.
然後叫他們畫出來。
Now you want me
to... describe it.
現在你想讓
我... 描述它。
And then you'll write it down,
and then what?
然後你會把它寫下來，
接下來呢？
-Mary...
-You'll let me go?
- 瑪麗——
- 你會讓我走嗎？
We all want the same thing here.
我們在這裡都想要同樣的東西。
We do.
沒錯。
We just want to find out
even a little bit more.
我們只是想
再多了解一點點。
What's gonna happen to me, Phil?
我會怎麼樣，菲爾？
That decision's not up to me.
那不是我能決定的。
So...
所以...
if we could just talk,
just you and me,
如果我們能談談，
就妳和我，
you know, just like...
just like two regular people.
妳知道的，就像...
就像兩個普通人一樣。
We could unpack some of this,
we've both been in there,
我們可以解開一些謎團，
我們都進去過那裡，
and-and-and get
on the same page.
而且-而且-而且
達成共識。
There are doors
opening everywhere.
到處都有
門在打開。
We don't know why
or what's connecting them.
我們不知道原因
或是什麼把它們連接起來。
(VOICE GETTING MUFFLED):
They sort of keep happening,
它們就這樣不斷出現，
and we don't know
how to stop them.
而我們不知道
該怎麼阻止它們。
(PHIL'S VOICE ALMOST INAUDIBLE)
(EERIE SOUNDSCAPE WITH
WIND CHIMES TINKLING SOFTLY)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLES
SLOWLY FADING OUT)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC OVERLAPPING
EERIE SOUNDSCAPE)
(LIGHTS BUZZING
IN THE BACKGROUND)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC
AND EERIE SOUNDSCAPE CONTINUE)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC FADES OUT)
(EERIE SOUNDSCAPE TURNS OMINOUS)
(OMINOUS SOUNDSCAPE TURNS
SINISTER THEN STOPS ABRUPTLY)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
( THE WORD BECOMES FLESH
BY BOARDS OF CANADA PLAYING)
CONTINUES PLAYING)
( THE WORD BECOMES FLESH
BY BOARDS OF CANADA ENDS)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(EERIE MUSIC ENDS)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC ENDS)